Hello friends and welcome to Northstella
wealth a video I'm discuss
super topup plan by ICI Lombard ICICI
Lombard activate booster in our previous
video I'm discuss
different super topup plan from
companies like Star Health HDFC Elbow
and Tata AIG also video I'm discuss
difference between a regular top-up plan
and a super topup plan so in the
previous video we have discussed super
topup And every company is now offering
super topup plan and also you can
understand the difference between
regular and top plan and super topup
plan. So discuss ICICI Lombard activate
booster
and I a chartered wealth manager and a
qualified personal finance professional
and I have been associated with this
insurance and investment industry for
the past a decade now. So let me share
my screen and understand what ICICI
Lombard activate booster is. What are
its features? How can we benefit it?
What is a super topo plan? How can we
take benefit of that super top plan
while taking a claim right so let's
start let me share my screen and let's
let us understand what is ICICI lumbar
acuate booster. So the plan provides you
maximum flexibility, maximum coverage. A
super plan which offers you two
different plan A and a plan B that will
help you to maintain your lifestyle
depending on that you can choose the
plan A or plan B. So first to understand
what is a super plan. So super plan will
cover all the expenses above your
aggregate deductible. So whenever you go
for a super top plan you have to define
your deductible for how much amount you
will not be claiming from this policy.
So deductible range in this policy
ranges from three lakh to 20 lakh and
beyond that you get a sum in short of 3
cr. For example you want a deductible of
two 20 lakhs and you can opt for 3 cr
and you get two different plan A and
plan B. So your base policy will be 20
lakhs and your top up policy can be of 3
cr. So all in all you will get a policy
of 3.2 cr. This plan offers you a unique
feature which is unique waiver of
deductible which will convert your base
policy at the age of 55 to 65. There is
a range of 55 to 65 in which you can
take this option. We will discuss this
further in future slide but you just
understand this option is available.
Plus there is no zone based co-ayment
across India. Plus there is a jump start
option which is an optional option where
you can prepone your pre-existing
disease. Generally health insurance
policy has a pre-existing disease
waiting period of 3 years but with this
feature you can prep it to 30 days and
after 30 days your pre-existing disease
will start getting covered. Now at a
glance if you see the biggest USPS are 3
cr some options is available which is a
huge cover waiver of deductible you can
convert that policy into your base
policy over a period of time and that
deductible reduction is 10% every
renewal plus there is no zone co-ay and
you get a PD cover in just 30 days by
paying some additional premium because
this is a optional feature of this plan.
So now let understand what play plan A
and plan B has to offer. Now if you see
the sum in short option here you get 10
lakhs to 3 crores with a deductible
option of three lakhs, four lakhs, five
lakhs, 7 and 1/2 lakh, 10 lakh, 15 lakh,
20 lakhs. In if you see the inpatient
hospitalization everything is covered
prehospization if you see 90 days is
covered in plan A 180 days post
hospitalization in plan B 60 days and 90
days domically hospitalization is
covered up to something short biatic
surgery is only covered in plan A.
Inpatient surrogate and okite is covered
up to 5 lakhs in plan A and it is not
covered in plan B. Home care treatment
is not covered in plan A and it is
covered in plan B up to five lakh. Wor
of deductible that is again an optional
is available in both the plan. You can
choose by paying that extra premium.
Nursing at home is again an optional in
plan B. Compensionate visit and health
checkup again it is available on plan B.
Under nursing at home you get 2,000
rupees per day max 10 days. So after you
are discharged from hospital you go to
your home then there is a requirement of
a nurse at home. So in that case this
amount is payable for next 10 days. So
this feature is available in plan B.
Compassionate visit again up to Rs.
20,000 is available for someone of your
family who wants to travel who wants to
visit you and uh can take this claim of
Rs. 20,000 and health checkup up to 50
5,000 is and health checkup up to Rs
5,000 is available for plan B.
Now how activate booster works? I'm
talking about this plan because this
works on an aggregate deductible. All
the claims in a year are counted
together.
Now supposedingly if you have a base
policy or if you have a corporate cover
of five lakhs this will work as a
deductible. Now if you take a activate
booster of 25 lakhs that will cover all
the excess claim right now you have a
combination of 5 lakhs and 25 lakhs. Now
the total protection is of 30 lakhs but
that will be at a fraction of cost
because the premium for activate booster
is quite less compared to a base policy.
Now let us understand what aggregate
deductible is. Reason being this is a
super topup plan and I have already
explained in our previous video how a
super topup aggregate deductible works.
Now here the deductible is 5 lakhs.
There is three different claims in the
same year. Now claim one is of two
lakhs. The first claim is not settled
because the amount is less than the
deductible. The second claim comes is of
one and a half lakh. The second claim is
also not covered under this because it
is less than the deductible. aggregate
is also coming to three and a half lakh.
Now supposingly there is a fourth claim
of four lakh rupees. Now the com now the
combined value of the claim is 7 and 1/2
lakh. Deductible is of five lakh. The
difference of 2 and a half lakh will be
paid by your super topo plan which is
activate booster in this case. The
remaining five lakh is getting claimed
from your base policy or your corporate
cover of 5x. So 5 lakhs gets covered
from your base policy and the 2 and 1/2
lakh gets covered from your activate
booster. So here this policy plays a
very vital role very important role so
that your pocket is not dented because
of that 2 and 1/2 lakh extra cost. Now
if you see the standout features of
activate boosters I explained you the
USP of waiver of deductible. Now if you
buy a policy before age 30 and if you
keep on renewing continuously the
company under this policy gives you a
option to convert the base policy with
zero deductible at the age of 55 to 65.
So your policy become fully future
proof. So you in the previous example we
understood five lakh was base policy 25
lakh was super top of policy and the
combination was 30 lakhs. Now if you
keep on renewing continuously at the age
of 55 you get an option that if you want
to get this complete policy of 30 lakhs
to be your base policy you can do that.
So here you get an option of waiver of
deductible. The second is jump start.
Your pre-existing disease are covered in
30 days. Now pre-existing disease like
ama, diabetes, hypertension, hyper
lipidmia, obesity can get covered within
just 30 days instead of 3 years by
paying that op extra premium. And this
is an optional benefit. You have to opt
for the jump start. Again, no zone based
co-ay, single premium, no deduction
based on city tire 1, tier 2, tier
three, tire four. No uh co-ayment is
allowed or there is a premium waiver or
premium uh discount anywhere available.
It is flat for across zone. Now again
there is a guaranteed deductible
reduction. Now if you opt for this
option, this is an optional option. If
you opt for this option, the deductible
reduces by 10% at every renewal up to a
maximum of 50%. For example, we have
understood that there was a base policy
of 5 lakhs. Now deductible reduces by
10% at every renewal. So over a period
of time the next year the deductible
will be 4 and 1/2 lakh next to next year
it will be four lakh 3 and 1/2 lakh
three lakh and 2 and 1/2 lakh 50% of
original deductible so your base policy
will become of 2 and 1/2 lakh and your
super topup will become of 27 and 1/2
lakh combined combination of your policy
will be 30 lakhs but the deductible will
be 2 and 1/2 lakh and 27 and 1/2 lakh
will be your super top up cover and the
biggest advantage here is one of the
highest summer short up to 3 cr is
available in a super topup plan in India
for HNI families benefit it is an OPD on
app you can download IIL which is IC
lumbar takeare mobile app and you can
aail discount on OPD pharma
physiootherapy diagnostic only through
that app so this facility is also
available now inbuilt coverage if you
talk about the inbuilt coverage inbuilt
coverage as I made you understand in the
previous slide
Inpatient hospitalization all the
expenses are covered due to illness,
injury or accident. Daycare procedures
are covered wherein less than 24 hours
are required for the treatment. Advanced
treatment, technological advancement
treatment, modern surgical and treatment
techniques is covered up to summing
short. Pre and post hospitalization is
covered in both plan A and plan B. IU
treatment is again covered. Ayurveda,
yoga, uninha is covered in both plan A
and plan B. Domestic road ambulance is
covered. Organ donor expenses donor's
hospitalization and surgery is covered
up to sum in short doicillary
hospitalization is also covered. So
inbuilt coverage benefit if you have
seen and again if you see the optional
cover which are available with this plan
is again jumpst start you can get your
cover pre-existing covered within 30
days. Bit you can get cashless OPD
pharmacy physotherapy and diagnostic at
a discount and a cashless basis on IC
lumbar take care app domestic air
ambulance is covered in both the plan
guaranteed deductible option I have
already explained teley consultation is
available and again there is a beauty
feature which is the inflation protector
now if you want a super topup plan if
supposedingly you have taken a super
topup plan of 25 lakhs if you opt for
that inflation protector every year your
some will keep on increasing as per the
medical inflation impact. The premium
will keep on rising. No doubt about
that. But again, you will not have a
stagnant insurance cover. It will keep
on rising. And that is a beautiful
feature of this uh this policy. Nursing
at home, I have already discussed it is
only available in plan B rupees 2,000
per day max 10 days. Compensionate visit
up to Rs. 20,000 for a family member to
visit during long hospitalization. This
is available in plan B only. Health
checkup again it is available in plan B
of deductible as I have already made you
understand if you buy a activate booster
before age 30 and if you keep on
renewing continuously at the age of 60
55 to 65 you get an option to convert
your deductible to zero. So no base
policy needed. You buy a policy at 50,
you renew continuously, you exercise
that option at 55 to 65 years of age.
Now your deductible becomes zero and
your complete protection will become
your base policy including your base
policy and your super top of policy. So
at the higher age it becomes very
important because you are getting a
bigger insurance cover. There will be no
medical test. There will be no telling
medical which will be there.
Automatically you get an option and you
can get it transferred to that policy.
Why this matter? Reason is your age.
Your base policy will become your super
top of policy. Now waiting periods again
every policy has the waiting period. 30
days initial waiting period will always
be there. After 30 days the cooling
period ceases and then your policy
starts and only for accidents it starts
from day one. For cardiac diabetes,
hypertension it is 90 days. uh for
specified disease it is again 2 years.
For biatic surgery it is again 2 years
and any pre-existing disease it is 3
years. You can prepone the specified
waiting for the pre-existing by 30 days
by taking jump start. Also many
discounts are available when you buy
this policy. There is a wellness
discount this is available on renewals.
N discount is available of 25%. There is
a civil score based discount which is
available of 15%. If you have a network
advantage, you get a discount of 10%
early renewal. If you renew the policy
early, uh this is available in the
renewal mode. Whenever the policy is
renewed, you get a 2 and a half%
discount. And again, long-term tenure,
you get up to 50% discount. If you opt
for two or three years of policy premium
together. So, you can also stack the
multiple discount wellness plus CV plus
long-term. So, you make a huge saving.
So again cashless uh claim process it is
cashless and reimbursement both you can
avail that facility you can visit the
network hospital and aail the cashless
claim if the hospital is not in the
network hospital then you can reimburse
your claim both facilities are available
now who should buy a activate boosters
as I explained it earlier if you are a
selleride employee with a corporate
cover if you have a corporate cover that
will become your deductible that will
become your base policy and over and
above the bigger cover will be your
super topup policy and if you are
planning for long-term you have a w of
deductible feature which means your
super topup policy will become your base
policy now if you have a pre-existing
disease like BP diabetes ama you have
that jump start option where you can
avail this facility high net worth
families because it offers 3 cr of
insurance cover you can opt for this
policy
so maximum flexibility maximum coverage
We at Nostella wealth provide you a
complete analysis of your base policy
and help you choose the right deductible
from three lakh to 20 lakh. It will is
our duty to provide you the right
feature whether a plan A is suitable for
you or plan B is suitable for you.
optional features like jump start, be
bait, deductible reduction etc is
available whether those options are a
are suitable for you because this
features with the optional riders which
you take will be extra premium it will
not come free anything extra anything
optional will increase your premium so
contact us at no level to get a
personalized activated booster
recommendation so guys this was all
about ICICI Lombard activate boosters
hope you have taken the cognizance of
all the features and whether these
features are beneficial for you or not.
And guys, if you have not subscribed to
our channel, do subscribe to our channel
because we bring to you such educational
videos and where we understand the this
kind of policies in details and help you
make the right decision. Thank you so
much guys for listening. Signing off
Mahindra Ra. Until we meet again.
Bye-bye.